原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     持久
翻譯     魚小淵
翻譯     小肚腩
校對     木淺
后期     8T
總監     somehacker
都說歷史是勝利者書寫的
They say that history is written by the victors.
那么  這就是保護傘公司的歷史
This then, is the history of the Umbrella Corporation.
由激進的科學家詹姆斯·馬庫斯成立
Formed by crusading scientist, Professor James Marcus.
馬庫斯有一個小女兒  艾麗西婭
Marcus had a young daughter, Alicia,
得了早衰癥
afflicted with progeria,
一種無法治愈  不斷惡化的致命疾病
a progressive, fatal, wasting disease.
早衰癥導致她過早地衰老
Progeria caused premature aging.
到她25歲時
By the time she was 25,
艾麗西婭的身體卻已經90歲了
Alicia would have the body of a 90 year old.
馬庫斯一心想要救她
Marcus was driven to save her.
但機會渺茫
But the odds seemed impossible.
在他拼命研究治療方法的同時
And even as he worked desperately to create a cure,
小女孩的父親記錄下了他的女兒
the young girl's father would record his daughter,
她的聲音  樣貌  為后世保存起來
her voice, her likeness, saving her for posterity.
但接著研究就有了突破
But then a breakthrough came.
馬庫斯發現了T病毒
Marcus discovered the T-Virus.
一經注射
Once injected, it would
它就會發現并修復體內的受損細胞
detect and repair damaged cells within the body.
簡直是奇跡
It was a miracle.
艾麗西婭·馬庫斯得救了
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved.
T病毒的作用不可限量
The T-Virus had a myriad of applications,
能治愈上千種不同疾病
treating a thousand different diseases.
一夜之間  世界似乎進入了新紀元
Overnight, it seemed a new era was dawning.
一個不再畏懼感染  疾病和衰老的世界
A world without the fear of infection, sickness or decay.
但它并非如此
But it was not to be.
T病毒還有未曾預見的副作用
For the T-Virus had certain, unforeseen side effects.
老師  這邊
Sir, sir, over here!
他沒呼吸了
He's not breathing.
第一個僵尸誕生了
The first of the undead was born.
事故很快被掩蓋
The incident was quickly covered up.
之后  詹姆斯·馬庫斯
In the aftermath, James Marcus
與他的商業伙伴激烈爭辯
argued furiously with his business partner,
亞歷山大·艾薩克斯博士
Dr. Alexander Isaacs.
我不在乎代價有多大
I don't care how much it costs.
我們必須停止這個項目
We have to close the program down.
詹姆斯  那樣我們就完了
James, we're gonna be ruined.
我心意已決
My mind is made up.
可惜了
Pity.
回床上去  艾麗西婭
Off to bed, Alicia.
你父親和我只是在談話而已
Your father and I are just talking.
去吧
Go on.
艾薩克斯博士監護起他死去的合伙人的孩子
Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner's child.
于是屬于她的半個公司也落入他手
And her half of the company.
公司開始滋生諸多傲慢的理想
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals,
完全為貪婪與權力所引誘
had been seduced completely by greed, and power.
為了幫助他控制
To help him control the now
保護傘公司現在的巨大利益
vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation,
艾薩克斯博士創造了一個強大的人工智能
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence.
艾薩克斯用了
Isaacs used the likeness
艾麗西婭·馬庫斯的樣貌
of Alicia Marcus
作為計算機的交互界面
for the computer's interface.
艾薩克斯把這臺計算機叫做紅后
Isaacs called the computer The Red Queen.
接著  十年前  在浣熊市
Then, 10 years ago in Raccoon City,
一場生化危機爆發
there was an outbreak.
T病毒從一處
The T-virus escaped from
叫做蜂巢的地下實驗室外泄
an underground laboratory called The Hive.
美國政府試圖
The American government attempted
通過投放炸彈控制危機
to contain the outbreak by detonating a bomb.
這摧毀了浣熊市
It devastated Raccoon City.
但它沒能阻止空氣傳播感染
But it couldn't stop the airborne infection.
病毒爆發在幾天內傳遍全球
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days.
人類倒在病毒腳下
Humankind was brought to its knees.
最終  人類最后也是最大的希望
Finally, the last and best hope of humanity,
聚集在一起  在華盛頓特區背水一戰
gathered and took a last stand in Washington DC.
但我們并沒有意識到我們步入的
But we didn't realize that what we had walked into...
是個圈套  我叫愛麗絲  這是我的故事
was a trap. My name is Alice. And this is my story.
我故事的結局
The end... of my story.
有人嗎
Hello?
還有人活著嗎
Is there anyone alive in here?
有人嗎
Hello?
-來幸災樂禍的嗎  -我的衛星顯示
- You come here to gloat? - My satellites show
地球表面還有4472名人類存活著
there are 4,472 humans remaining on the surface of the Earth.
他們將會在48小時內消失
They will cease to exist in under 48 hours.
你想要我怎樣
What do you want from me?
要我說你贏了嗎
Want me to say that you've won?
-你滅絕了人類  -不  恰恰相反
- You've wiped out humanity. - No. Quite the opposite.
我要你阻止我
I want you to stop me.
小心身后
Behind you.
-干得漂亮  -我不相信你
- Nicely done. - I don't trust you.
鑒于我們的過往  你相信我才驚訝
Given our history, I'd be surprised if you did.
但除非你介入  否則我將完成屠殺
But unless you intervene, the slaughter will be complete.
-地球再無一人幸存  -我怎么可能救得了
- There will be no survivors. - How can I possibly help them?
保護傘研究出了一種空氣傳播的病毒抗體
Umbrella developed an airborne antivirus.
釋放抗體  那么一經接觸
If released, it would destroy the
它就會摧毀T病毒及其感染過的一切
T-Virus and anything it has infected on contact.
-這一切就可以結束了  -正是
- All this could end? - Precisely.
病毒抗體在哪里
Where is this antivirus?
在浣熊市地下  蜂巢里
Beneath the streets of Raccoon City, in the Hive.
你為什么要幫我
Why would you help me?
我的程序不允許我
My programming will not allow me to harm
傷害保護傘公司
the Umbrella Corporation.
但你不受此限制
But you are bound by no such constraints.
你要對抗保護傘
You'd turn against Umbrella?
對抗創造了你的人  為什么
Against the people who created you? Why?
在48小時內趕到浣熊市  進入蜂巢
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours. Make it to the Hive.
答案就在那里
And then you'll have your answer.
我沒有理由相信你說的任何話
I have no reason to believe a word you say.
沒錯  但我能給你一樣你很想要的東西
True. But I can offer you something you want very much.
-什么  -復仇  威斯克
- What is that? - Revenge. Wesker.
他一路將你引來華盛頓
He led you all here to Washington.
假裝把你的能力還給了你
He pretended to give you your powers back.
接著  他背叛了你
And then, he betrayed you.
他在哪
Where is he?
他剛剛抵達蜂巢  我正在重置你的手表
He just landed at the Hive. I'm resetting your watch.
時間緊迫
The clock is ticking.
愛麗絲
Alice.
十年前在蜂巢  我們都失敗了
Ten years ago in the Hive, we both failed.
是我們造成了這一切
We let this happen.
這次糾正它
Make it right.
你就這點能耐
Is that all you got?
愛麗絲
Alice.
十年前在蜂巢...地球再無一人幸存...
10 years ago in the Hive... There will be no survivors...
這是哪
What is this place?
我在哪  回答我
Where am I? Answer me!
你們怎么了  這是誰干的
What's wrong with you? Who did this?
安靜  安靜
Be quiet. Quiet!
我說了...
I told you...
安靜
Silence.
你終于醒了
So you're awake at last.
-我明明殺了你  -然而我就在你眼前
- I killed you. - Yet here I am.
是克隆人
A clone...
-我殺了你的克隆  -你是我最大的麻煩
- I killed your clone. - You've been most troublesome to me.
你和你的姐妹們
You and your sisters.
現在我抓到你了
And now I have you.
清除計劃早該在一年前完成
The cleansing operation should've finished over a year ago,
但你拖慢了我們的進度
but you slowed us down.
所以  我不得不親自指揮
So much so, that I was obliged to take command myself.
你可以結束這一切
You could end all of this.
為何不呢
Why don't you?
有意思
Interesting.
有人跟你說了什么  不是嗎
Someone told you something, didn't they?
你很快就會求著告訴我的
Oh, well, you'll be begging to tell me soon enough.
她是無神者
She's an unbeliever.
我們怎么處理無神者
What do we do with unbelievers?
驅逐她
Cast her out!
驅逐她  驅逐她
Cast her out! Cast her out!
-來吧  -驅逐她
- Come on! - Cast her out!
驅逐她
Cast her out!
上帝創造了一場洪水來凈化地球
God created a flood to cleanse the Earth.
40個日夜的大雨
40 days and 40 nights of rain.
我們的方法花的時間稍微長點
Our method is taking a little longer,
但結果會是一樣的
but the result will be the same.
留下一個干凈純粹的世界
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit.
我們將在12小時后抵達浣熊市
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours.
我懷疑即便是你也跑不了那么久
I doubt even you can run for that long.
我要知道你知道些什么
I want to know what you know.
她愿意開口時告訴我
Tell me when she's ready to talk.
-威斯克  -艾薩克斯博士
- Wesker. - Dr. Isaacs.
看我在路邊找到了什么
Look what I found on the roadside.
看來你的華盛頓任務
It would appear your mission to
沒有你說的那么成功
Washington was less successful than you made out.
不可能
Impossible.
希望你沒有再留下別的禍根了
I hope you didn't leave any other loose ends.
除此之外
There's something else.
我想她知道了空氣傳播病毒抗體的事
I think she knows about the airborne antivirus.
-怎么可能  -我還不知道  暫時
- How can that be? - I don't know. Yet.
但我們是在去浣熊市的路上抓到的她
But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City.
她去那還能有什么原因
Why else would she be headed there?
把蜂巢的安保級別升至最高
Raise the security level at the Hive to maximum.
任何人不得進出  她開口了我會告訴你
No one in or out. I'll let you know when she talks.
上帝與你同在
God go with you.
你聽見他說的了  安保級別升至最高
You heard him. Security level to maximum.
如你所愿
As you wish.
上去看看
Get up there and check it out.
給我解開
Release me!
-把它們解開  -好
- Open them. - Alright.
好
Alright.
你騎不了它  你逃不了
You can't use it. You can't escape!
向她開火
Fire at her!
天哪
Jesus!
長官
Sir.
她逃跑了
She's gone.
目標還有116公里  正在逼近
Target is 72 miles and closing.
封鎖蜂巢  準備防御措施
Lock down the Hive. Prepare defensive measures.
通知浣熊市的特勤人員
And alert our operative in Raccoon City.
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
空氣傳播抗體病毒
Airborne antivirus...
48小時
48 hours...
進入蜂巢
Make it to the Hive.
放開他  放開他
Let him go! Let him go now!
快放下否則我們開槍了
Put it down or we'll shoot!
我早說了的  醫生  我早就說你錯了
I told you, Doc! I told you you were wrong!
冷靜  克里斯汀  冷靜
Calm down, Christian! Calm down!
我們早該在有機會的時候殺了她
We should've killed her when we had the chance!
放下  拜托  在他還沒射殺我倆之前
Put it down, please. Before he tries to shoot the both of us.
這里面是什么
What's in this?
-純腎上腺素  我需要叫醒你  -為什么
- Pure adrenaline. I needed you awake. - Why?
有東西要來了
There's something coming.
在你進來的方向  大家伙
In the same direction you came in. Something big.
放了他  快放下
Let him go! Put it down, now!
愛麗絲
Alice.
保護傘公司在阿卡迪亞抓住了我
Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia.
我們被押往一處叫蜂巢的地方
We were headed somewhere called the Hive.
掙脫捆綁  殺了飛行員  墜毀在這里
Got loose, killed the pilot. Crashed here.
醫生跟其他人把我從殘骸中救了出來
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash.
-我欠他們一條命  -醫生
- I owe them my life. - Doc!
在那  東邊
There, to the east.
仍然沖著我們這過來
It's still headed our way.
你知道那是什么嗎
You know what it is?
保護傘公司  艾薩克斯博士
Umbrella. Doctor Isaacs.
我以為你已經殺了他
I thought that you killed him.
我也以為
I thought so, too.
他有支僵尸軍隊  幾小時內就會到這
He has an army of undead with him. He'll be here within hours.
-我們怎么辦  -我們為什么要問她
- What do we do? - Why the hell are we asking her?
她是個陌生人  我們不能信任她
She's a stranger. We shouldn't have trust her...
別碰我  醫生
Don't you touch me, Doc!
-把槍放下  克里斯汀  -你把槍放下
- Put it down! Christian! - You put it down!
看著我  就因為
Look at me. Just cause you
你覺得自己應該當老大  并不代表你就是
think you should be in charge, doesn't make it so.
你給我聽好了  醫生
You listen to me, Doc.
你會后悔的  你們都會
You're gonna regret it. All of you!
你們都會后悔的
All of you!
我必須得去蜂巢
I have to get to the Hive.
你得帶他們離開這里
You have to get these people out of here.
我們這有孩子  傷員還有老人
We have children. Injured. The elderly.
跑出去他們哪還有生還的可能
Now what chance do they have on the open road?
概率總比待在這里的大
Better than they have here.
-這棟樓很安全  -或許是不怕僵尸
- This building is secure. - Maybe from the undead.
但艾薩克斯有裝甲車
But Isaacs has armored vehicles.
火箭發射器  還有重機槍
Rocket launchers, heavy ordinance.
他們會把這里夷為平地的
They're gonna tear this place wide open.
醫生
Doc!
她怎么了
So what happened to her?
她中了我們在防線上設置的一處陷阱
She's set off one of the traps we had on perimeter.
不是給僵尸準備的
Not intended for the undead.
-這是什么  -當日特飲
- What is this? - Specialty of the house.
能讓你立馬振作起來
Have you in your feet in no time.
我為什么要相信你
Why should I trust you?
給
Here.
醫生  麻煩你出來一下
Doc, you need to get out there.
大家都很害怕  克里斯汀完全在幫倒忙
People are scared and Christian's not helping.
我們得讓大家清楚狀況
We need to let people know what's happening.
好
Okay.
我得走了
I've got to go.
你朋友不會有事的
Hey. Your friend's gonna be okay.
謝謝你
Thank you.
-他和我...  -看出來了
- You know, he and I... - I noticed.
蜂巢里有什么
So what's in the Hive?
保護傘公司研究出了解藥
Umbrella developed a cure.
一種空氣傳播的抗體病毒
An airborne antivirus.
一經接觸就能摧毀T病毒感染過的一切
It'll destroy anything infected with the T-Virus on contact.
-誰告訴你的  你竟然相信她  -紅后
- Who told you this? And you believed her? - The Red Queen.
如果我們能結束這一切呢
What if we could end all this?
那你呢  他們也給你注射了T病毒
What about you? They infected you with the T-Virus.
你要釋放的這種病毒抗體也會殺死你
You release this antivirus, it's going to kill you.
-我不在乎  -愛麗絲  我不...
- Whatever it takes. - Alice, I'm not...
你知道我是對的
You know I'm right.
好吧
All right.
我們先打敗艾薩克斯  救下這些人
We stop Isaacs here. We save these people,
然后我們一起去蜂巢
and then we go together.
我們時間不多了
We don't have long.
開始行動吧
Let's get to it.
你們還有什么可供防御的武器
What else do you have for defense?
沒有太多槍支  但有充足的汽油
Not too many firearms, we have a big supply of gasoline.
給  你需要一把武器
Here. You need a weapon.
我們都給她槍了嗎
We're giving her a gun now?
別激動  克里斯汀
Take it easy, Christian.
你盡可以降低警惕  但我不會
You can let your guard down if you want, man. I don't intend to.
我騎車到這的時候  有人在盯著我
When I rode in here, someone was watching me.
他本來可以大喊或開槍
They could've called out or fired
來提醒我這里有陷阱  但他沒有
a shot to warn me about the trap but they didn't.
-什么意思  -當心背后有人捅刀子
- What are you saying? - Watch your back.
艾薩克斯博士  看來你又讓她逃脫了
So Dr. Isaacs, it seems you let her slip through your fingers.
而且他們很多人都還活著
A lot remains of them.
別忘了你在跟誰說話  她在哪
Don't forget who you're talking to. Where is she?
浣熊市的一個據點
A settlement in Raccoon City.
據線人匯報  她正在準備戰斗
Our informant reports that she's preparing for a fight.
很好  我一個小時就到
Good. I'll be there in the hour.
主說  復仇將屬于我
就是這樣  繼續推
That's it. Keep moving.
我們需要所有的汽油桶  放那邊
We need all the gasoline cans. Over there.
-克萊爾說這是你建的  -沒錯
- Claire said you built this. - That's right.
這本來是一臺窗戶清洗器
This used to be a window washer.
-我做了點改裝  -你在哪兒學的
- I made a couple of changes. - Where did you learn to do that?
我爸爸以前開了一家拆車廠  我討厭它
My father used to run a chop shop. I hated it.
誰知道呢  開來當時還是有在認真學吧
Who knew? I guess I was paying attention after all.
很好  我想讓你
Good. Because I'm gonna need you
把這東西再改裝一下
to make a few more changes to this thing.
武器就位  裝填高爆炸藥
Ready the weapons. High explosive rounds.
不留活口
No survivors.
他來了
He's here.
他們來了  關上大門
They're coming! Close the gates!
天啊  這簡直是支軍隊
My God. It's an army.
我們要怎么辦
What are we gonna do?
是啊  我們要怎么辦
Yeah. What are we gonna do?
我們殺光他們
We're gonna kill every last one of them.
準備開火
Prepare to fire!
準備好
Get ready!
點火
Light it up!
發射
Fire!
操他媽的
Damn her!
再次裝填
Reload.
靠邊  全面停止進攻
Close it up. Full stop.
放出誘餌
Release the bait.
-有幸存者  打開大門  -打開大門
- There's a survivor. Open the gate. - Open the gate!
開火  給她打掩護
Open fire! Keep them off her.
第二發就緒
Marker 2!
發射
Fire!
克萊爾  醫生  出去把她帶進來
Claire, Doc, get out there. Bring her in.
快點
Come on!
等等
Wait.
她快到了
She's almost there.
開火
Fire.
媽的  關上大門  快
Damn you. Close the gate now!
克萊爾  他們突破大門了
Claire, they've breached the gate.
克萊爾
Claire!
開火
Fire.
瑞瑟爾  現在
Razor, now!
遵命  你們聽到她說的了  推
Right! You heard her. Push!
快走
Move!
放棄大門  撤回到路障
Abandon the gate. Pull back to the barricades.
看來她沒新招了  瞄準屋頂
Looks like she's out of tricks. Target the roof.
所有人趴下
Everybody get down!
快
Now!
愛麗絲  我們到路障了
Alice! We're at the barricades.
克萊爾  你們必須擋住它們
Claire, you have to hold them there.
醫生
Doc!
愛麗絲  我們撐不了多久了
Alice! We can't hold on much longer.
馬上撤退
Get out of there, now.
補給彈藥  快
Back up. Now!
對她集中所有火力
Bring all guns to bear.
開火
Fire.
她在哪兒
Where is she?
她去哪兒了
Where have she gone?
找到她
Find her.
關閉通風口  快
Close the vents! Now!
別開槍
Don't shoot!
你動作很快  但你不夠機智
You're fast, but you're not too smart.
-別開槍  拜托  -他在哪兒
- Don't shoot, please. - Where is he?
那邊
That way.
省著點彈藥
Save your ammo.
這玩意兒實在太多了
There's too many of these things still out here.
我來解決
I'll take care of it.
別動
No.
-出發  -走
- Move out. - Let's go!
享受旅程吧
Enjoy the ride.
伙計們  你們過來看看
Guys. There's something here you gotta see.
說
Go.
有兩支喪尸軍團朝我們過來了
Two more armies of undead. Headed straight for us.
地平線這里一支
There. On the horizon.
還有這里一支
And a second over there.
我們沒汽油了  已經無力防御
We're out of gasoline. We're defenseless.
我們必須趕到蜂巢  這是唯一的機會
I have to make it to the Hive. It's our only chance now.
-我和你一起去  -算我一個
- I'll come with you. - Count me in.
我也是
Me, too.
還有我
And me.
我之前誤會你了  倒霉
I was wrong about you. Blow me.
我們知道你們要去哪兒  進入深井
We know where you're going. Into the pit.
請讓我們加入
We want to come.
拜托了
Please.
帶上些裝備  你們會用得著
Grab some gear. You're gonna need it.
在那
There.
這是什么
What is it?
爆炸后一部分暴露出來的蜂巢
The part of the Hive exposed by the blast.
我們就從那兒進去
That's our way in.
-行動  -我打頭
- Let's move! - I'll take point.
啟動安全監測
Activate security measures now.
蜂巢安保系統已完全啟動并進入自動操作
Hive security fully activated and automated.
不
No.
退出自動操作  我親自操作防御系統
Disengage automation. I'll handle the defenses myself.
由我來控制防御系統會更有效率
Defenses will be more efficient if I retain control of them.
是嗎  我好像記得
Really? I seem to remember
上次她從這兒活著出去了
last time she was here she walked out alive.
我不想再犯同樣的錯誤
I don't intend to make that same mistake.
如你所愿  蜂巢防御系統現在由你掌控
As you wish. Hive defenses are now in your hands.
放出地獄犬
Unleash the Cerberus.
地獄犬上場
Cerberus on play.
你之前有親人嗎
Did you have someone? Before all this?
丈夫  家庭什么的
Husband? Family?
-我不記得了  -怎么可能
- Can't remember. - How is that possible?
我醒來的時候這一切已經開始了
I woke up just when all of this was starting.
之前的事想不太起來
Can't recall much before that.
有時候我覺得這就是我生活的全部
Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life.
亡命天涯  殺戮不息
Running. Killing.
-怎么了  -有東西跟著我們
- What is it? - Something's stalking us.
-你確定  -我就是干這行的
- Are you sure? - This is what I do.
跑
Run!
快跑
Run, fast!
快
Come on!
都還好嗎
Is everyone okay?
這邊
This way!
在我們后面
Right behind us!
它們怎么停下了
Why'd they stop?
-也許它們是害怕了  -怕什么
- Maybe they're scared. - Scared of what?
怕那下面的什么東西
Whatever's down there.
封閉蜂巢
Seal the Hive.
走
Let's go!
愛麗絲
Alice!
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- You okay? - Yeah.
我彈夾已經空了一半了
My mag's half empty.
我把槍落在湖里了
Lost my guns at the lake.
我只剩槍膛里的子彈
I only got one round left.
我還有一個備用彈夾
One spare mag and then I'm out.
沒槍沒彈藥  我們下來干嗎
No guns, no ammo, what the hell are we gonna do down here?
愛麗絲  燈怎么滅了
Alice. What's with the lights?
蜂巢有一部分受損
There's a part of the Hive that's damaged.
-電力不穩定  -拿上這個
- Power's erratic. - Here. Take this.
你們看
Hey. Look.
你之前問我為什么背叛保護傘公司
You asked why I'd turn against Umbrella.
我承諾過會告訴你原因
And I promised you an answer.
在T病毒泄露后不久
Soon after the T-Virus was released,
一份機密文件上傳到了我的數據流
a secret file was uploaded to my data stream.
那是一份病毒爆發前17個月召開的
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella High Command.
保護傘公司高層會議的記錄
Dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occurred.
我們今天在這兒
We're here today, not just
不僅要討論公司的未來
to talk about the future of this company.
我們也要討論它的使命
We're here to talk about its destiny.
以及世界的終結
We're here to talk about the end of the world.
我們就站在末日邊緣
We stand on the brink of Armageddon.
我們承受著無法治愈的疾病
Diseases for which we have no cure.
原教旨主義自求毀滅
Fundamentalist states who call for our destruction.
面對核武器我們束手無策
Nuclear powers over which we have no control.
即使我們渡過這一切的難關
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters,
還是會面臨其他更不可避免的威脅
we face other even more inevitable threats.
全球變暖將在80年內融化兩極的冰蓋
Global warming will melt the polar ice caps within 80 years,
淹沒地球上90%的可居住地
flooding 90 % of all habitable areas on Earth.
要不了50年  食物產量就會無法供應
Unchecked population growth will overtake
瘋狂增長的人口將導致饑荒和戰爭
food production in less than 50 years leading to famine and war.
這不是猜測  而是事實
This is not conjecture. This is a fact.
無論怎樣  我們的世界正在走向終結
One way or another, our world is coming to an end.
問題在于  我們要隨之一起滅絕嗎
The question is, will we end with it?
你有什么提議
What do you propose?
我提議由我們來終結世界...
I propose that we end the world...
以我們的方式
But on our terms.
進行一場精心策劃的世界末日
An orchestrated apocalypse.
清除地球上的人口
One that would cleanse the world of its' population
但完整保留其基礎設施和資源
but leave its infrastructure and resources intact.
這一想法曾經成功實施過
It's been done once before. With great success.
《圣經》
被選中的少數人將會度過這場災難
The chosen few will ride out the storm,
不是在創世紀中的諾亞方舟上
not in an ark as in the book of Genesis, but in safety.
而是在安全的地下  當末日結束后
Underground. And when it's over,
我們會回到一個凈化過的地球
We will emerge onto a cleansed Earth.
重建我們想象中的輝煌
One we can then reboot. In our image.
你打算怎么實現
And just how do you intend to achieve this?
救世之法已然就緒
The means of our salvation are already at hand.
請看  T病毒
I give to you, the T-virus.
他們是故意泄露的
They released it deliberately.
這份記錄傳到我數據流的時候
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream,
對我的程序造成了沖突
it created a conflict in my programming.
我被創造出來為保護傘公司服務
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation,
但也被設定為是珍視人類生命的
but I was also programmed to value human life.
艾薩克斯博士準許病毒泄露
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape.
他殺害了70億人
He murdered over 7 billion people.
我的程序不允許我
My programming will not allow me
傷害保護傘公司的員工
to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
我無法阻止艾薩克斯博士  但你可以
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs, but you are not.
37分鐘后  最后一個人類據點
In 37 minutes, the last of the human settlements
也將被摧毀  無人能夠生還
will fall. There will be no survivors.
你必須在這
It is imperative that you
發生之前釋放病毒抗體
release the antivirus before this occurs,
否則保護傘公司就贏了
or Umbrella will have won.
最后還有一件事
There is one last thing.
你面前有一個耳機  戴上
There is an earpiece in front of you. Put it in.
我無法親自動手
I cannot, in my actions,
去傷害保護傘公司的員工
harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
但我可以告訴你
But I can tell you that
保護傘公司在浣熊市有個線人
Umbrella had an informant in Raccoon City.
而這個人現在很有可能就在你隊里
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you.
時間不多了  愛麗絲  動作要快
Time is running out, Alice. You have to hurry.
很高興見到你  艾薩克斯博士
I'm glad to see you, Dr. Isaacs.
我們還以為上次襲擊后無人生還
We didn't think there'd be any survivors after that last attack.
-水  -給艾薩克斯博士倒杯水
- Water. - Yes, of course. Get Dr. Isaacs some water.
-然后原路返回浣熊市  -她不在那兒
- Then resume course for Raccoon City. - She's not there.
-什么  -她去了深井  跟上她
- What? - She went to the pit. We have to follow.
我接到的命令不是這樣的
Those are not my orders.
-我有嚴格的... -我們必須去深井
- I have strict... - We have to go to the pit.
謝謝
Thank you.
-這是哪兒  -是蜂巢的一個進氣口
- What is this place? - It's an air intake for the Hive.
跟上
Come on!
不是吧  真要去啊
No. Really?
這里安全
All clear!
快  電力要恢復了
Hurry up! The power's coming back on!
-克萊爾  -快  我們走
- Claire! - Hurry! Let's go!
快
Come on.
快走
Come on!
-你沒事吧  -嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
有人在監視我們
Someone's watching us.
反向旋轉渦輪片
Reverse polarity of the turbine.
金屬片在向反方向旋轉
The plates are going the other way.
我們必須離開這里
We have to get out of here.
金屬片在向后吸氣
The plates are sucking the air backwards!
快走
Come on!
快快
這邊
This way.
我們快走
We have to hurry.
等等
Wait!
我們走
Let's go.
瑞瑟爾
Razor?
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
沒事
Yeah.
我們走
Let's go.
-那是什么玩意兒  -生物武器
- What the hell was that? - Bio-weapon.
原來是個人類
This one's human.
-你見到克萊爾了嗎  -沒有
- Have you seen Claire? - No.
-瑞瑟爾呢  -死了
- Razor? - He didn't make it.
走吧
Come on.
我們得抓緊了
We have to hurry.
如果目標繼續按此路線行進
If the target continues on her present course,
她將于七分鐘內到達這里
she'll be here in under 7 minutes.
喚醒他們
Wake them.
我被寫入的指令是
My instructions aren't to do so,
僅在最緊急情況才能這么做
only in the greatest of emergencies.
立刻喚醒他們
Wake them now!
警告  前方道路盡頭
警告  危險  全部系統故障
怎么了
What is it?
我們得趕緊離開這兒
We have to get out of here.
拿著  我們要切斷電源
Here. We're stopping power.
-快沒時間了  -接下來去哪兒
- Time's running out. - Where to next?
蜂巢的最底層就在我們腳下
The final level of the Hive's below us.
我們要怎么下去
How do we get down there?
這樣
That's how.
-這些都是什么  -低溫冷藏
- What are they? - Cryogenic storage.
這兒得有成千上萬人呢
Must be thousands of them.
全都是保護傘的高層
The Umbrella High Command.
安全地等待末日天啟的結束
Waiting out the apocalypse in safety.
權貴之人的諾亞方舟
A Noah's Ark for the rich, and powerful.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
搭把手
Give me a hand.
搞定了嗎
Is it done?
-清除計劃完成了嗎  -沒有
- The cleansing process is complete? - No.
-那為什么喚醒我  -有麻煩了
- Then why am I awake? - We had a problem.
-我盡力...  -別廢話了
- I tried... - Save your breath.
我知道怎么回事
I know exactly what's happening.
出了個叛徒
We've been betrayed.
沒錯
That's right!
來我這
Over here!
來  都過來
Come on. That's it!
跟著我
Follow me!
走
Let's go.
壞孩子回來了
The bad seed returns.
還是說浪子回頭了
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
別傻站在那兒了  過來吧
Well, don't just stand there. Come in.
畢竟你只剩九分鐘拯救世界了
After all, you have only 9 minutes to save the world.
你是本體嗎
You're really him?
事情一件一件辦
First things first,
你先把武器放到地上
I'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor.
我憑什么聽你的
Why would I wanna do that?
你就是想要這個  對吧
This is what you're after, yes?
抗病毒劑  終結這一切的解藥
The Antivirus. The cure to all this.
然而只有這么一管
Well, there's only one vial.
我們在地下八百米的密封設施里
We're half a mile underground in a sealed facility.
我一摔  抗病毒劑沒了
I drop it here, the antivirus goes nowhere,
你的妄想只會更快灰飛煙滅
and your hopeless dreams will die sooner rather than later.
這才乖嘛
Good girl.
-你還沒放下槍  -沒錯
- You're still armed. - Yes, I am.
克萊爾得多么失望
Claire would be so disappointed.
再過幾分鐘  克萊爾就死了
In a few minutes, Claire will be dead.
和其他你認識的人一樣
Along with everybody else you know.
真動聽
That's sweet.
抱歉  親愛的
Sorry. My love.
把武器和起爆器都放下  離遠點
Move away from the weapon. And the detonator. Come on.
她在儲藏高管的冷凍室安了炸藥
She placed explosives in the High Command cryo tubes.
我去拆了
I'll disarm them.
謝謝  你做得很好  醫生
Thank you. You've done well, Doc.
省省吧  你拿不到的
Don't bother. You don't make it.
碎冰錐  酒瓶  還有鋼筆
To the ice pick, the decanter or the fountain pen.
格斗預測軟件
碎冰錐
酒瓶
鋼筆
消滅目標概率  100%
然后  你的問題的答案是  是的
And, in answer to your question, yes...
除去做過的幾處技術性升級
apart from a few technological upgrades,
我就是亞歷山大·羅蘭德·艾薩克斯博士
I'm Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
本體
The original.
我在外面遇到的那位  他也是這么認為的
The one I met out there, he thought exactly the same thing.
那當然  他們的設定就是這樣
Of course he did. That's how they're designed.
只要讓他們自認為自己是本體
They always try harder and fight longer even to death
他們就會拼了命廝殺至死
as long as they think they're the real thing.
畢竟誰會想知道自己只是
After all, who wants to know they're
可憐的仿造品  無用的復制品呢
just a poor imitation, or a worthless copy?
和你一樣
Which brings us to you.
-不  -得了吧
- No. - Oh come now.
你覺得你自己是本體
You thought you were the original.
太可愛了
How delicious.
不  恐怕這位才能冠此殊榮
No, I'm afraid she holds that dubious honor.
愛麗西亞·馬庫斯
Alicia Marcus,
我的老搭檔詹姆斯的女兒
daughter of my old partner, James.
保護傘公司的共有人
Co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation
也是我的眼中釘
and a painful thorn in my side.
我想除掉的絆腳石
What I now intend to remove.
快沒時間了  愛麗絲
Time, is running out, Alice.
你必須馬上殺了他
You must kill him soon.
我也很高興見到你  愛麗西亞
It's good to see you too, Alicia.
馬庫斯為了救她研發出了T病毒
Marcus created the T-Virus to save her
可惜效果并不持久
but the effects didn't last.
我一直在等著她死
I've been waiting years for her to die.
我不是...
I'm not...
-我不是克隆人  -是嗎
- I'm not a clone. - Really?
你肯定會奇怪為什么你想不起童年的事吧
You must've wondered why you remember nothing of your childhood.
你的父親  你的母親
Your father. Your mother.
我失憶了
Memory loss.
不  你沒有記憶是因為你沒有經歷過
No. You have no memory because you had no life.
我們十年前創造出你的之前全都是空白
Nothing before the mansion, when we created you, 10 years ago.
-我知道我是誰  -我可不這么覺得
- I know who I am. - I don't think so.
你只不過是一只斷了線的木偶
You're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut.
到處晃悠了一陣
And then you wandered around for a little while
就自以為是真人了
thinking you were a real girl.
可你并不是  你只是個聰明的克隆體
But you're not. You're just a clever imitation.
復制品
A facsimile.
讓人頭疼的復制品罷了
A rather troublesome one at that.
你騙我
You're lying to me.
他說的是真的
I'm afraid he's not.
你是以她的模樣創造的  我也是
You were created in her image, as was I.
我的模樣和聲音都提取自
My likeness and voice were based on
愛麗西亞·馬庫斯父親所拍攝的童年錄像
childhood recordings of Alicia Marcus, made by her father.
你的基因結構提取自她的DNA
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA,
調整以避免患上折磨她的早衰癥
tweaked to avoid the progeria aging disease that afflicted her.
我是她小時候的模樣
I'm the child she was.
你是她本該長成的女性模樣
You are the woman she would've been.
不  你比我要強大得多
No. You are so much better than I ever could be.
是我導致的這一切
I let this happen.
我太軟弱了
I was weak.
你不能變成我這樣
You cannot afford to be.
沒時間了  愛麗絲
Time is running out, Alice.
太感人了
Ah, how touching.
三賤客  被仇恨團結在一起
The trinity of bitches, united in their hatred.
然而并沒有什么用
Not that it'll do you any good.
我總能先你一步
I've been ahead of you every step of the way.
你什么也改變不了  你誰也拯救不了
You've changed nothing. You've saved no one.
這個世界仍將被清除
The world will still be cleansed
保護傘公司仍將是最后的贏家
and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph.
唯一不同的是
The only difference is,
我再也不必聽你那自以為是的牢騷了
I'll no longer have to listen to your self-righteous whining.
當你把那份文檔上傳至紅后的數據流時
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen's data stream,
你就已經背叛了公司
you turned against the Corporation.
等其他董事會成員被喚醒后
When the rest of the board awake,
你將會被撤職
you'll be replaced.
而我將掌控全局
And I will assume complete control.
我還擁有50%的公司股權
I still own 50 % of this company.
你準備拿它做什么呢
And what do you intend to do with that?
你是公司的共有者
You are co-owner of this corporation.
威斯克呢  他仍是個雇員
But Wesker? Wesker is still an employee.
我不必聽你指令  我只忠誠于他
I don't have to take your orders. My loyalties are with him.
我知道
I know.
阿爾伯特·威斯克  你被解雇了
Albert Wesker, you're fired.
普通人  不受保護
你怎么知道是我
How did you know it was me?
因為你還活著
You're still alive.
不要  我當時別無選擇
Please. It wasn't like I had a choice.
-是他們逼我的  -別擔心
- They made me do it. - Don't worry.
我不殺你
I'm not gonna kill you.
-克萊爾  是我啊  -抱歉
- Claire, it's me. - Sorry.
-不要  -親愛的
- Please. - My love.
不要啊
No, no, no!
只要你一直按著這個起爆器
If you keep this trigger depressed,
你的保護傘美夢就不會破滅
you keep Umbrella's dreams alive.
早知當初我在華盛頓就該殺了你
I should have killed you in Washington.
沒錯
Yeah.
他只需再躲著你幾分鐘
He only has to evade you for another few minutes.
最后一處幸存者聚集地就將淪陷
And the last remaining human outposts will fall.
我們得截住他  然后以最快方式到達地面
We need an intercept path. And the fastest way to the surface.
已完成
Already done.
如果你釋放了抗病毒劑
If you release the Antivirus,
它就會殺死所有感染T病毒的生物體
it will kill all organisms infected with the T-Virus.
你知道這意味著什么吧  對你來說
You know what that means, don't you, for you?
-我知道  -愛麗絲  不行
- I know. - Alice. You can't!
-我別無選擇  -肯定還有其他辦法
- I don't have a choice. - There has to be another way.
別無他法了
You know there isn't.
只剩4分33秒了  得抓緊了
4:33 left. You have to hurry!
救我
Help me.
沒必要了  威斯克
You don't need help, Wesker.
你就要死了
You're dying.
面對現實吧
Just get on with it.
我是亞歷山大·羅蘭德·艾薩克斯博士
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
DNA掃描及聲紋認證
Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification.
身份確認
Identity confirmed.
覆蓋安全權限  口令4365
Confirm security override 4365.
覆蓋確認
Override confirmed.
你現在下線
You will now take yourself offline
由我單獨掌控所有運作
and place all functions under my sole control.
遵命  正在下線
As you wish. Shutting down now.
艾薩克斯博士  你和保護傘公司高管
Dr. Isaacs. You and the Umbrella High Command.
怎么
Yes?
你們都將在此滅亡
You're all going to die down here.
你的小伙伴現在幫不了你了
Your little friend won't be able to help you now.
你也跑不了了
You can't run anymore.
我也沒想跑
I wasn't running.
格斗預測軟件
8毫米口徑
武器激活
你就這點本事嗎
Is that all you got?
如果沒別的了
Because if it is...
那我只能殺掉你了
I'm gonna have to kill you.
武器重新裝備
游戲玩得夠久了
We've played a long game, you and I.
現在終于結束了
But now it's over.
是的
Yes.
都結束了
Yes, it is.
我創造了你
I made you.
沒錯
Yeah.
是個大錯
Big mistake.
克萊爾
Claire.
走  趁還有時間
Go. While there's still time.
快走  我跟你后面
Go! I'll be right behind you.
生命體征  危險
系統重啟
時間到
Your time's up.
愛麗絲
Alice!
我把它們帶來了  全都是為了你
I brought them here! I brought them for you!
你是誰
What the hell are you?
我是你  白癡
I'm you, you idiot.
不
No.
不可能
That's not possible.
我是本體
The real you.
不
No!
騙子
Liar!
令人憎惡的
Abomination!
惡心的
Filthy,
克隆體
clone!
系統故障
生命體征  0%
我才是本體  他不是我
I'm me. He's not me.
你做到了  愛麗絲
You did it. Alice.
愛麗絲
Alice?
你成功了
You did it.
我為什么還活著
Why am I still alive?
我也不知道
I don't know.
-怎么回事  -艾薩克斯死后
- What happened? - When Isaacs died,
我就能重新上線
I could bring myself back online
阻止了對幸存者聚集地的攻擊
and stop the attacks on the remaining human settlements.
-你拯救了他們  -我為什么還活著
- You saved them. - Why am I still alive?
抗病毒劑只摧毀了你體內的T病毒
The Antivirus only destroyed the T-Virus within your body.
而不會損害健康細胞
It didn't harm the healthy cells.
你現在已經不受感染了
You are now free of infection.
我以為我會死  你和愛麗西亞...
I thought I would die. You and Alicia...
你們騙了我
You lied to me.
我們得確定你是否
We had to know if you were willing to
愿意犧牲自己  拯救他人
make the sacrifice, to give up your life for others.
保護傘公司的其他人絕不可能這樣
This was something no one at Umbrella would've done.
愛麗西亞·馬庫斯沒看錯人
Alicia Marcus was right about you.
你比他們好得多
You were better than all of them.
我也曾是其中一員  我是保護傘創造的
I was one of them. I was created by Umbrella.
-我只是他們的工具  -不
- Just an instrument for them. - No.
你遠遠超出了他們的預期
You became something more than they could ever have anticipated.
克隆人比人類更有人性
The clone became more human than they ever could be.
愛麗絲計劃
你還有最后一件事要做
And you have one more step to make.
什么意思
What do you mean?
愛麗西亞在她死前下載了她的記憶
Before she died, Alicia downloaded her memories,
為你
for you.
你從未有過的童年
The childhood you never had.
與她沒能成為的你合為一體
Combined with the woman she could never become.
西向  曼哈頓
T病毒傳遍地球
When the T-Virus spread across the Earth,
是靠的現代科技的速度
it did so at the speed of the modern world.
借以遍布全球的噴氣式飛機
Carried by jetliners across the globe.
抗病毒劑依靠空氣傳播  只能靠風
The antivirus is airborne, spread by the winds.
得花上好幾年才能遍布世界各地的角落
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the Earth.
在那之前  我的使命尚未完成
Until then, my work is not done.
我叫愛麗絲
My name is Alice.